Dheemanth A.N.

dheemanth.simha01@gmail.com +91 7019817873 Bengaluru, Karnataka,India

Summary

Young professional currently pursuing a Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and a **Full Stack Web Developer**, building excellent products.

Ex SDE summer intern at J.P. Morgan Chase & Co | Ex QA intern at Brane Enterprises |

Experience in working with **complete software development lifecycle**, right from planning and requirement analysis to deployment.

Keen interest in tech, fitness, and an adventurous biker exploring trails, offroads, and unexplored marvels.

Education

B.E. Computer Science and Engineering

Dayananda Sagar College Of Engineering [2019-2023] • Bengaluru, Karnataka CGPA – 9.14 [Till Sophomore year]

Science - PCMC

Sadhana PU College • Bengaluru, Karnataka **Pre University Topper** . **97.33%** in PCM .Overall **96.8%**.

03/2019

Class 10 CBSE

Prarthana Education Society • Bengaluru, Karnataka Secured 10 CGPA .Recipient of Letter of Appreciation from CBSE Board. 03/2017

Technical Skills

- Development constructs: React, NodeJS, Express, EJS, Redux, Bootstrap
- Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Python, Solidity
- Markup language: HTML
- · Stylesheet Language: CSS
- Scripting Languages: Javascript
- IT Constructs: Data structures and Algorithms, OOPS, REST API
- Development tools: Microsoft Visual Studio Code, Git, Github, Gitpod, cURL, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, Geany, Ganache, Truffle Suite, Remix IDE
- DB language: MySQL,MongoDB
- API development and Testing tools: Postman, Jest, SuperTest, Grafana, Thunder client, Chrome dev tools
- Deployment : Heroku, Netlify, Railway, Github pages
- Project Management and Documentation : Atlassian Confluence, Jira, Github Projects

Industry Experience

Summer Intern

J.P. Morgan Chase & Co • Bengaluru, Karnataka

• Role: Full Stack Web Developer

05/2022 - 07/2022

- 1. Tech Stack: React, Java, Maria DB, Node JS
- 2. **Testing**: Mockito, Chai
- 3. Line Of Business: Corporate
- Part of JPMC's **Global Real Estate Team** and worked on an internal **property management website** for JPMC's clients.
- Worked on an entire project lifecycle, right from understanding requirements, to planning, development, testing, and deployment.
- **Built an API** to replace the previously hard-coded value in the frontend application to now fetch the value from the database and help in future scalability.
- Worked on a real-time, deployed project, housing many Fortune 500 companies' assets and properties, and enhanced the project by implementing a well-tested scalable, and robust API for seamless changes and updates.

Quality Assurance Intern

Brane Enterprises [NSL HUB] • Hyderabad, Telangana

09/2021 - 04/2022

- Involved in manual testing of solutions, performed a total of 950+ tests in Smoke Suite and Regression Suite test
 cases.
- Identified critical bugs in the platform and thoroughly documented the steps to reproduce the bugs.
- Part of the **automated testing team** created automated test scripts **in Postman** which **reduced** the overall **testing time** by **10–15 minutes**.

Projects

1) ThoughtRoom [MERN stack + Redux] View the site

A **blogging web app** powered by **REST architecture** and a platform to study, comprehend, like and share ideas. Designed with an elegant UI/UX and a seamless platform to blog about a multitude of topics.

Tech Stack

- Languages/Frameworks: ReactJS,ExpressJS,NodeJS,MongoDB,Mongoose,Redux+Redux Toolkit for State Management
- Implementation: JWT token based authentication and authorization along with refresh tokens, database password hashing using bCrypt, CORS, cross-environment development, protected routes and deployment via Railway.

2) AntiCorruption Ledger [Blockchain and Web3] View the project on Github

An end-to-end, foolproof ledger that can track all the incoming and outgoing transactions pertaining to a cause.

This blockchain-based web app **allows users to track where their money** is being spent which is often a question mark whenever a user makes a donation to an NGO or a cause. The primary use case is to **achieve 100% transparency and eliminate corruption** completely in donations and legal tenders.

Tech stack

- Languages/Framworks: ReactJS, NodeJS, Solidity, CSS, Express
- Other tools: Axios Library, Truffle Suite, Ganache [Local Blockchain], Ethers js library, Metamask, Remix IDE, Json-Server

3) Portfolio [Web Development] View the site

A terminal styled thematic website developed in order to showcase my professional work and a go to place to learn more about me and my work.

Designed the layout according to a **tab based style of navigation**, coupled with a **responsive well adaptive design** with smooth transitions, followed by **deployment on netlify**.

Tech stack

- Language/Framework: ReactJS
- Other tools: React Router, Netlify[Deployment]

Certificates and Achievements

- Internship offer from J.P Morgan Chase & Co after developing a solution for NGO-Uninhibited [view project] in 24 hours with total participants of 6000 students across India.
- Participated in Hackverse by NIT Surathkal [view certificate] and built Discourse-a debating app.
- Participated in Flipr Hackathon [view certificate] and built a Gmail clone [Frontend] in React.
- Participated in inter-college Hackathon [view certificate] by Department of CSE, DSCE and built a solution for parking problems faced by students in colleges.
- Course completion certificate [view certificate] after an intensive coursework of 200+ hours on Full Stack Web Development using MERN from University of Helsinki, Finland.